Here we have the iceCreamTotals object,
لدينا هنا كائن iceCreamTotals،
which shows the total number of gallons of ice cream
والذي يظهر العدد الإجمالي لغالونات الآيس كريم
that each member of the Udacity Web team has eaten.
التي قد أكلها كل عضو من فريق موقع Udacity.
Veronica with 600, Jessica 818, David over 9,000.
فيرونيكا 600، جيسيكا 818، ديفيد أكثر من 9000.
Richard didn't seem too accurate.
لا يبدو أن ريتشارد دقيقًا للغاية.
Let's go ahead add a couple more zeros onto him.
لننطلق ونضيف زوجين أكثر من الأصفار عليه.
Wonderful.
رائع.
Now let's say I wanted an array of just the keys in this iceCreamTotals object,
لنفترض الآن أنني أردت مصفوفة من المفاتيح فقط في كائن iceCreamTotals هذا،
meaning that I want an array of only Veronica,
مما يعني أنني أريد مصفوفة من فيرونيكا فقط،
Andrew, Jessica, David, and Richard.
أندرو وجيسيكا وديفيد وريتشارد.
What we can do is to call Object.keys and pass in the iceCreamTotals object.
ما يمكن أن نقوم به هو استدعاء Object.keys وتمريرها عبر كائن iceCreamTotals.
Let's go ahead and do that.
لنتابع ونفعل هذا.
You can see how the return value of calling Object.keys and passing iceCreamTotals,
يمكنك رؤية كيفية قيمة إرجاع استدعاء Object.keys وتمرير iceCreamTotal،
gives us an array of all the keys in that original object.
والتي تعطينا مصفوفة من جميع المفاتيح في ذلك الكائن الأصلي.
Now, what if we wanted just an array of values of this object?
الآن، ماذا إذا كنا نريد مصفوفة واحدة فقط من قيم هذا الكائن؟
Well similarly, we can just hit
حسنا فبالمثل، يمكننا فقط الضغط على
Object.values passing the same object. We can get that array.
Object.values لتمرير نفس الكائن. يمكننا الحصول على تلك المصفوفة.
And here we have it, we have the array of just the values 600 all the way
لدينا هنا مصفوفة من القيم 600 فقط حتى نهاية المسار
to 10 million for Richard. All right.
حتى 10 مليون لريتشارد. حسنًا.
So that was just a very clean,
كان ذلك مجرد مسح،
very quick way of doing things to get the key values.
طريقة سريعة جدًا لتنفيذ هذه الأشياء للحصول على القيم الأساسية.
What we also could have done was just do a for in loop to build our own array.
ما كان بإمكاننا القيام به أيضًا هو مجرد عمل تكرار حلقي من أجل إنشاء مصفوفة.
Similar to the original setup,
على غرار الإعدادات الأصلية،
we have the iceCreamTotals object,
لدينا كائن iceCreamTotals،
same information but now this time what we're doing
نفس المعلومات ولكن ما نفعله الآن
is creating our own results array that are going to build up,
هو إنشاء مصفوفة النتائج التي سيتم بنائها،
and then iterating through the iceCreamTotals object with a for in loop.
ثم التكرار من خلال الكائن iceCreamTotals بواسطة تكرار حلقي.
And now, if you check the result array,
والآن، إذا قمت بفحص مصفوفة النتيجة،
you'll see that it gives us the same output.
فسترى أنها تعطينا نفس الناتج.
Let me go ahead and put this side by side.
دعني أنطلق وأضع هذا جنباً إلى جنب.
Notice that the result of the array that we build ourselves gives us
لاحظ أن نتيجة المصفوفة التي قمنا بإنشائها بأنفسنا تعطينا
the same output as the Object.keys call we made originally.
نفس ناتج استدعاء Object.keys الذي أنشأناه في الأصل.
Using Object.keys gives us the same result as if we loop through it ourselves,
يعطينا استخدام Object.keys نفس النتيجة كما لو كنا ننفذ التكرار من خلاله بأنفسنا،
but it's a little bit more readable and also a lot less code to write.
لكنه أكثر قليلا في قابليته للقراءة وأيضًا أقل كثيرًا في كتابة الأكواد.